David Cotelessa

310 E. Providencia Ave Apt #214, Burbank CA 91502 | <u>david@cotelessa.com</u> | 323 839 0272

Summary

I'm a Javascript Developer, with a focus on UI, as well as backend with AWS. My experience has ranged from building and maintaining more single page web applications to web components and more robust websites for advertising, automotive and healthcare.

Skills

Languages	Libraries	Frameworks	Tools
Javascript	Webpack	React	AWS
CSS	Serverless	Redux (React)	DynamoDB
HTML	Express	Angular	PostgreSQL
Node	Iodash	-	-

Work Experience

Hixme | Agoura Hills, CA | http://www.hixme.com

position: Javascript Engineer | February 2017 - March 2019

technology used: Node, Javascript, React, Redux, Serverless, AWS (DynamoDB, S3, Lambda), HTML/CSS/JS, Webpack, VSCode, git, vim

I developed and maintained the front end experience for a startup healthcare company, comprised of internal tools for staff and consumer tools for employees and HR. The backend is comprised of many tools but mostly Amazon Web Services and other serverless tools, which has evolved me to be more of a full-stack developer. I was able to update much of the front end of the site alongside my team to the latest version of Redux Forms (v5 to v6), add more testing to the project, build new editors for data for staff and clients.

MXM | Los Angeles, CA | previously: Genex | parent company: Meredith | http://meredithxceleratedmarketing.com position: Full Stack Developer | September 2015 - October 2016 | clients: Ford.com

technology used: Adobe Experience Manager, Javascript, HTML/CSS, Angular, Webpack, Atom, git, svn

I developed web components from wireframes and specifications from the Ford design team with several frontend and backend developers, some on-site and others outsourced. I gained familiarity with the Java backend platform Adobe Enterprise Manager. Each component also was responsively designed to handle both mobile and desktop browsers, and include code for page analytics, tracking, and geolocation. I helped the team find workflow solutions to keep the project on schedule. I also researched other frameworks for possible future projects with MXM.

iCrossing | Santa Monica, CA | parent company: Hearst Publishing | http://www.icrossing.com position: UI Engineer | April 2015 - August 2015 | clients: Toyota.com

technology used: Javascript, HTML/CSS, Lodash, Docker, Atom, git, svn

I maintained and updated web applications for Toyota. On a team of several backend and frontend developers in an agile environment. The primary goal was to optimize and update the performance of the site, replacing and removing legacy code from previous iterations of the site.

72andSunny | Los Angeles, CA | http://72andsunny.com

position: Frontend Developer | April 2014 - March 2015 | clients: Google, Starbucks, Target, The Truth Project, 72andSunny technology used: Javascript, Actionscript, HTML/CSS, Flash, git

I was on a in-house team of developers creating html and banner ads, helping out project managers in learning best practices as well as helping on internal projects to build responsive web applications.

Work Experience (cont.)

Heavenspot | Glendale, CA | parent company: M&C Saatchi | http://www.heavenspot.com

position: Frontend Developer | November 2013 - March 2014 | clients: Netflix, Warner Bros,(CW), NBC/Universal, RocketDog technology used: Actionscript, Javascript, HTML/CSS, PHP, Flash

Transitioning my skills to Javascript while still working on Flash games and ad banners, I developed web applications and content management themes for content managed websites.

TBWA\CHIAT\DAY | Los Angeles, CA | previously: \TEQUILA | parent company: Omnicom | http://tbwachiatdayla.com position: Interactive Developer | March 2004 - October 2013 | clients: Nissan, Infiniti, Energizer, Grammys, Jimmy Dean, Visa, Pepsi, Gatorade, Playstation, Pennzoil, Kraft, Uncle Ben's, Principal Financial, Crate & Barrel, Apple technology used: Actionscript, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Flash

Working from design comps and collaborating with design and developer teams, I mostly built banner ads and client websites, ranging from the simple to very complex, complete with inline video, games, and other interactivity, and delivered across many ad portals, like Doubleclick and Sizmek. Some banners were developed with MSN and Yahoo to takeover their sites' front pages. During that time, I developed my own Actionscript code to be reused for many of the projects.

(there's more work experience between 1994 - 2002 all related to entertainment website building and media authoring.)

Other Experience and Interests

Volunteering at the Magic Castle | http://www.magiccastle.com

I volunteered at the Los Angeles magicians' clubhouse to update and maintain their website with other volunteers, as well set up a live streaming services on their for the general meetings to service members. I also help professionally record events as a service to visiting performers and members.

Consultant for Wordpress and Drupal sites | http://www.finesseremodeling.com and http://www.koltikvah.com technology used: HTML/CSS, PHP, MySql/MariaDB, git, npm

It comes as no surprise that people ask me for help to build a website; I've helped them using familiar LAMP stacks, and build custom plug-ins to ensure they can maintain their own websites with less effort and minimal knowledge of its inner workings.

Meetups with Coders https://www.meetup.com/javascriptla

Hanging with fellow coders at various Meetups have helped me connect and learn about exciting new code, platforms, technologies. Also, the geek and pop culture factor is very high, which is very comfortable for me.

Tinker with Arduinos and Raspberry Pis

On weekends I'm not reading a tutorial on some new technology, I build little machines. One of my weekend projects was a pen plotter using two recycled DVD drives.

Education

University of California, Irvine | Irvine, CA

graduated: Bachelor of Arts | major: Studio Art | 1989 - 1994 | also studied: Computer Science, Japanese I studied programming and early Web design before transferring majors to Studio Art, studying illustration and creative thinking. I also worked at the campus newspaper as ad publisher and layout artist, creating local ads. I co-founded a campus club for the promotion of animation (mostly Japanese anime), Cal Animage Epsilon, which still has meetings.

Portfolio and Links

Github | https://github.com/dcotelessa

JSFiddle | https://isfiddle.net/user/dcotelessa

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-cotelessa-3431b96

Codepen https://codepen.io/dcotelessa/